Preliminary Guide to the Paul M. Gross papers, 1939-1979 UA.05.53.0001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Accssion number: A93-43
  - Emeritus payments, correpsondence, general correspondence (Box 17)
  - Administrative Committee, minutes and meeting notes (Box 17)
  - Duke Endowment (Box 17)
  - 50th Anniversary materials (Box 17)
  - Speech by Gross dedicating the Fritz London auditorium (Box 17)
  - General study materials (Box 17)
  - Committee on Educational Institutions (Box 17)
  - Paul Clyde correspondence, mostly concerning faculty compensation, general university matters, 1962-1967 (Box 17)
  - Memo to President Arthur Hollis Edens regarding faculty salaries, 1953 (Box 17)
  - Duke University Development
    - General correspondence and reports (Box 17)
  - Ratings of universities in the U.S. (Box 17)
  - Chemistry Department (Box 18)
    - Graduate papers, 1927-1940 (Box 18)
    - Correspondence, 1933-1934 (Box 18)
    - General materials, 1949-1960 (Box 18)
  - Phi Lambda Upsilon (chemistry honor fraternity) (Box 18)
  - Sigma Xi materials (Box 18)
  - Chemistry Department, general files, 1960-1964 (Box 19)
    Includes correspondence, notes, reports, and minutes from various Duke University committees, professional organizations, and other university chemistry departments.
  - Chemistry Department, general files, 1964-1967 (Box 20)
  - Woodrow Wilson fellowship meetings, 1968-1969 (Box 20)
  - Awards letters of recognition, and some meeting notes (Box 21)
    - Woodrow Wilson fellowship meetings, 1970-1973 (Box 21)
    - U.S. Army award, 1963 (Box 21)
    - Herty Award correspondence, 1945 (Box 21)
  - Southern Association of Science and Industry, 1951 (Box 21)
  - Lecture/talk to the American Chemical Society, Florida section, 1952 (Box 21)
  - Committees
    - American Council on Education, 1963 (Box 21)
    - University Council, 1960-1961 (Box 21)
    - Executive Committee of Academic Council (Box 21)
    - Chemistry Library (Box 21)
  - Paul Gross Symposium, 1965 (Box 21)
  - Retirement dinner of Paul Gross (Box 21)
  - Dr. Henry Heald's speech, 1965 (Box 21)
  - Letters of congratulations, 1949-1950 (Box 21)
  - Graduate records, 1941-1946 Joe Taylor Adams, correspondence and subject files (Box 22)
  - Selective service, correspondence and subject files, 1940-1949 (Box 22)
  - Joseph Allen, correspondence and subject files (Box 22)
  - CRESAP report on organization and administration of Duke University (Box 22)
  - Gross speech (Box 22)
  - Founder's Day 50th Anniversary, 1975 (Box 22)
  - Southern Association of College and Secondary Schools, 1947-1950 (Box 22)
  - Association of American Universities, 1948-1949 (Box 22)
  - Graduate School, correspondence and subject files, 1951-1952 (Box 22)
  - Committees (Box 23)
    - Undergraduate Affairs Committee (Box 23)
    - Faculty Advisory Committee (Box 23)
    - University Planning Committee (Box 23)
  - University Council (Box 23)
  - New science building (Box 23)
  - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 23)
  - Duke Endowment, 1968-1969 (Box 23)
  - Senator Lister Hill's Testimonial, 1961 (Box 23)
  - Various reports on environmental health, radiological health, and toxicology, ca. 1961 (Box 23)
  - Committees (Box 24)
    - Environmental Health Committee (Box 24)
    - President's Science Advisory Committee (Box 24)
    - Various reports for Gross Committee, ca. 1961 (Box 24)
    - Development Program at Duke University (Box 24)
  - Claude Cary Gravatt, Jr., Ph.D. student, writings and correspondence committee materials (Box 24)
  - Departmental reports, ca. 1959 (Box 24)
  - Medical Center Building Committee reports, ca. 1959-1960 (Box 25)
  - Correspondence
    - President R.L. Flowers (Box 25)
    - Dean Wannamaker (Box 25)
    - Social Science Research Council (Box 25)
    - Gross-Edens reports and correspondence (Box 25)
  - Apparatus research Atomic Industrial Forum Conference Award, 1969 (Box 25)
  - Subject files on furniture manufacturing and textiles (Box 25)
  - Testimonial dinner for Paul M. Gross, 1959 (Box 25)
  - Paul M. Gross Chemical Laboratory dedication, 1969 (Box 25)
  - U.S. Atomic Energy Award, single (Box 25)
  - University Council on Aging and Development (Box 25)
  - President Arthur Hollis Edens correspondence, reports, subject files, ca. 1959 (Box 25)
  - General University organization (Box 25)
  - Faculty Senate, ca. 1951 (Box 25)
  - Navy contract, superconductivity, 1947-1948 (Box 25)
  - Duke University committees (Box 26)
    - Committee on Development (Box 26)
    - Educational Committee (Box 26)
    - Committee on Faculty Reorganization (Box 26)
    - Long-Range Planning and Development (Box 26)
  - Departments and Schools reports (Box 26)
  - Travel abroad, 1958-1969 (Box 26)
  - Northwestern University National Academy of Sciences (Box 26)
  - Chemstrand Research Laboratories Dedication, 1961 (Box 26)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, congratulations on being selected to serve as President-Elect (Box 26)
  - Duke Symposium (Gross was a panel speaker) (Box 26)
  - Dinner in honor of Dr. Lucius Bigelow, 1961 (speech in box 2) (Box 26)
  - Conference given in honor of Dr. W.C. Davison, 1961 (speech in box 2) (Box 26)
  - Bylaws of Duke University, revisions, ca. 1961 (Box 27)
  - Salary increase discussion, 1961-1962 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence
    - President Douglas M. Knight (Box 27)
    - Thomas L. Perkins, ca. 1961-1971 (Box 27)
    - Commercial vendors (Box 27)
    - UNESCO-related (Box 27)
    - Massachusetts Institute of Technology (Box 27)
- Accession number: 65-28
  - Duke University, departments and committees (Box 28)
    - Academic Standards Committee - Committee Appointments (Box 28)
  - Paul Hibbert Clyde (Box 28)
  - Columbia University (Box 28)
  - Duke Mathematics Journal (Box 28)
  - Duke University, departments and committees (Box 29)
    - Computation Center - Engineering, 1954-1955 (Box 29)
      Includes Divinity School and Department of Education
    - Engineering, 1956-1975 - Faculty (Box 30)
      Includes Department of English and enrollment statistics
    - Faculty member lists - Graduate School (Box 31)
      Includes German Department and School of Forestry
    - Graduate School, foreign language requirement - Libraries, Flowers Collection (Box 32)
      Includes History Department and Law School
    - Mathematics Department - Medical Center (Box 33)
    - Medical Center, staff, correspondence, subject files (Box 34)
    - Medical Center - Parapsychology Laboratory (Box 35)
      Includes Nursing School
    - Parking and Traffic - Psychology Department (Box 36)
      Includes Physical Education (from Women), Physics, and Political Science
    - Psychology Department - Romance Languages Department (Box 37)
      Includes Registrar, Religion Department, and Research Council
    - Romance Languages Department - Sociology and Anthropology Department (Box 38)
      Includes space allocation, and summer session
    - Sociology and Anthropology Department - Zoology Department (Box 39)
      Includes University Council and Woman's College
  - Duke University Press (Box 39)
  - DuPont Grants for Advancing Undergraduate Teaching (Box 39)
  - President Arthur Hollis Edens correspondence, 1949-1958 (Box 39)
  - Fidelity Bank branch establishment (Box 40)
  - Correspondence
    - Ford Foundation (Box 40)
    - Herbert Herring (Box 40)
    - John J. Gergen (Box 40)
    - Edwin Hobbs (Box 40)
    - Charles E. Jordan (Box 40)
    - Alan K. Manchester, 1949-1959 (Box 40)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1949-1958 (Box 40)
  - Highland Biological Station (Box 40)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1954-1957 (Box 41)
  - Southern Regional Education Board files, 1949-1954 (Box 41)
  - Southern Regional Education Board files, 1954-1959 (Box 42)
  - National Defense Education Act, 1958-1959 (Box 42)
  - Fulbright scholarships, 1950-1959 (Box 42)
  - Yale University teaching (Box 42)
  - This box is unprocessed. (Box 43)